Guide to the Fred Henry Sexauer papers, [ca. 1928]-1978.
Sexauer, Fred Henry papers, [ca. 1928]-1978.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Fred Henry Sexauer papers, [ca. 1928]-1978.
3026
Fred Henry Sexauer, 1891-
22.6 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, reports, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, photographs, reports, and related original source material concerns Sexauer's career as an agricultural leader and documents his work with organizations including the Dairymen's League, the National Council of Farmer Cooperatives, and the National Milk Producers Federation. There is also information relating to New York Highway Users and improvement of rural roads.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Sexauer was born in Kingston, Illinois and came to New York in 1914. In 1915 he purchased a farm outside of Auburn, N.Y. Soon after starting farming, he became active in a local cooperative, and in 1919 became a director of the Dairymen's League's Cooperative Association (now Dairylea, Inc.). In 1921 he was elected to the League's executive committee and in 1928 became President. During the Roosevelt administration, he played an active role in the Committee for the Nation and the Committee for Constitutional Government.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, photographs, reports, and related original source material concerns Sexauer's career as an agricultural leader and documents his work with organizations including the Dairymen's League, the National Council of Farmer Cooperatives, and the National Milk Producers Federation. There is also information relating to New York Highway Users and improvement of rural roads. Individuals mentioned include Edward Rumely, Frank Gannett, and Ezra Taft Benson.
Also, "Currents in the Life of Fred H. Sexauer," (6 volumes with index), an inscribed copy of Stable Money by Irving Fisher, and an inscribed copy of "Eastman's Chestnuts."
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sexauer, Fred Henry, 1891-; Benson, Ezra Taft.; Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947.; Gannett, Frank E. (Frank Edward), 1876-1957.; Rumely, Edward A. (Edward Aloysius), 1882-; Committee for the Nation.; Dairymen's League Cooperative Association.; National Committee to Uphold the Constitution (U.S.); National Council of Farmer Cooperatives.; National Milk Producers Federation.
Subjects:
Agriculture and politics.; Milk--Cooperative marketing.; Dairying, Cooperative--New York (State); Dairying--Economic aspects.; Rural roads--New York (State); Farmers.
Places:
United States--Politics and government--1919-1933.; United States--Politics and government--1933-1945.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Printed matter-save and incorporate into collection (Box 1)
- F. Sexauer personal files A-Z, mostly 1930s and 1940s (Box 2)
- Misc. material, 1940s-1950s (Box 3-4)
- Conference of National Organizations, 1949-1957 (Box 5)
  As President of Dairy League, Sexauer was a member of this group, which met regularly - organization is not really known to the public so the proceedings, etc. should be valuable.
- Addresses of F. Sexauer, 1931-1943 (Box 6)
- Addresses of F. Sexauer, 1928-1930 (Box 7)
- Some Ed Rumely material, 1957-1958 (Box 7)
- Committee for the Nation - some printed and mimeo items, 1933-1934, 1937 (Box 7)
- Dairy League items plus Ezra Taft Benson (Box 8)
- Mostly Dairy League, 1950s and 1960s (Box 9-10)
- Committee for Constitutional Government, 1946-1954 (Box 11)
  The organization was after Committee for the Nation, Ed Rumely (good stuff here).
- Committee for Constitutional Government, mostly 1950-1953 (Box 12)
- Speeches, 1940-1950 (Box 13)
- Dairy League (Box 13)
- Food and Freedom, Ezra T. Benson, F. Gannett, American Agriculturalist (Box 13)
- Parity, 1945 (Box 14)
- League (Box 14)
- Comm. for Constitutional Government (Box 14)
- America's Future, Inc. and Food and Freedom (Box 14)
- Dairy League, 1930s and 1940s (Box 15)
- J.J. Dillon re: D. League history (long letter), 1935 (Box 15)
- Rumely material in (TIP folder) (Box 15)
- FDR letter dated Apr. 18 taks for views on monetary situation, interested in enclosure, 1938 (Box 15)
- Confer. of National Organizations, 1948- (Box 16)
- Some on agriculture, A. Goss and A. Klein, 1948 (Box 16)
- Committee on National Organizations (Box 17)
- Comm. for Constitutional Government (Box 17)
- Correspondence of F. Sexauer, 1919-1920, 1954-1958 (Box 18)
  Includes Committee for Constitutional Government - John Taber, H. Lehman, H. Newsom.
- Pictures - take out of frames (Box 19)
- Printed - distribute to G. and Exch. (Box 19)
- NY Highway Users (improve rural roads) (Box 20-21)
- Printed matter - distribute to G. and Exch. (Box 21)
- 3 posters with information regarding milk prices, surplus and the role of the Dairyman's League (Map-case Items)
  On fabric backings